- Previously on Gotham...
- My name is Volk. My brother Jacob.
We are called the Whisper Gang.
Those men were willing
to kill for this key,
- but what does it open?
- A safe.
Inside, there is a device that
we believe can destroy them.
They call themselves
the Court of Owls.
Isabella was murdered.
Her brake lines were cut!
And I know who did it.
You can stop the blade
from being released.
If you click this button, it will send
a fatal jolt to Butch.
Hey, Butch, you're sweet.
- You really didn't kill her?
- No!
- Guilty!
- The lab analyzing
Alice Tetch's blood
has developed a test.
- You're kidding.
- Don Falcone, please.
We'll pull your car around.
Carmine's not the target.
You are. Get down!
Why are you coming
after me?! You know why.
Why are you trying to kill my son?
We will expect your
assistance when called on.
Until then, your son is
safe... At least from us.
Why does it feel like
we keep saying good-bye?
Maybe it's all we have left.
Or we just haven't done it properly yet.
Bye, James Gordon.
She loves him, she loves him...
You lost?
She loves me...!
Hey.
I'm getting married tomorrow.
Congratulations.
People always talk about
love at first sight.
I never believed it.
But the moment I saw her, I knew.
Yeah.
So, what do you do?
I'm a hematologist.
At Gotham Bio-Lab.
You aren't working on that blood virus,
are you, from, um...
what's her name? Tetch?
Alice Tetch?
Uh, my fiancée is with
the police department.
She's the medical examiner on the case.
Oh. Yes.
She said
you had come up with
a test for the virus.
I really can't talk about it.
She almost married someone else.
I think her ex still hopes she'll come
running back.
Not gonna happen.
She loves him.
She loves him. She loves him.
Do you hear me, Jim?
I won't let you have her!
- Sync and corrections by madhatters -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Volk is dead?
We found his and Dmitry's bodies
early this morning.
They were killed Talon,
the Court's assassin.
Well, that certainly changes
things a bit, doesn't it?
How? You possess the key.
The key opens the safe.
Inside the safe is an object
that can bring down the Court of Owls.
None of this has changed.
If this assassin saw us with Volk...
That means the Court already knows
that you're breaking
your deal, Master Bruce.
I wish we knew for certain.
Yeah, well, I wish we knew
for certain what was in
that blinking safe or how
far we can trust this little
Whisper Gang front.
Ask yourself this:
Is bringing down the Court
really worth the risk?
The Court of Owls has
taken over my company,
threatened people I care about,
and is likely responsible
for my parents' deaths.
What's our next step?
I'm giving this one to Alvarez.
No.
I told you to take the day off.
I know.
You do know I'm acting
captain now, right?
Yeah.
Jim, there will be another
dead body tomorrow.
Seriously, take the day.
Go fishing, get drunk.
Harvey, this is my job.
Lee getting married doesn't change that.
Take a look at this guy's head.
Whoa. What's that coming out of his ear?
His skull was crushed.
Like someone squeezed
it from either side.
Can you imagine the
strength needed to do that?
I got to tell you, my first thought...
- Oh, no.
- Barnes.
Stop it!
Barnes had the virus. He's at Arkham.
That story's over. This
is what I was afraid of.
Wallet's here, but the killer
took a badge or something
from around his neck.
Your emotions are all stirred.
You're seeing things
that aren't really there.
This is just a classic case
of wrong place, wrong time.
One man takes another man's skull
in his bare hands and crushes it.
I see it all the time.
Receipt... from the cafeteria
at Gotham Bio-Lab, where
Alice Tetch's blood
is being tested.
- Crap.
- I'm gonna swing by.
Finish up here, will you?
Sure, Jim. Happy to oblige.
No rest for the wicked.
Relax.
I'm not here to get revenge
for you lopping off Tabby's paw.
Though I am surprised to find you
back at work and not
tracking down who really did
kill your lady love.
That's because you don't
see the full picture.
The mayor has many enemies.
These enemies understand that I am
a fundamental part of this operation.
They weaken me, they weaken him.
That was clearly the
intent of killing Isabella.
Also, I have spies
all over this city.
Soon enough, whoever killed Isabella
will reveal themselves,
and I will strike.
Poor blind baby.
It's always hardest to see
what's right under our noses.
Penguin!
Did you just fake cough "Penguin"?
Needless to say,
that is... absurd on a number of levels.
Really?
All a crime requires is
means, motive and opportunity.
And your beaky little buddy
certainly has the means and opportunity.
But no motive.
Oh, I would say he had the
oldest motive in the book.
"Rich men want it,
wise men know it, the
poor all need it..."
Love. What does that have to do...
And the penny... drops.
You are suggesting...
that Oswald...
is in love with me?
- That is ridiculous.
- I know. I mean,
personally, I find you a
bit of a cold fish, but...
Ozzie saw you being taken away
from him by that bookish vixen,
and...
Aah... oh, no!
Hmm.
No.
In fact, I'm beginning to wonder
what your motive is in all this.
That's for later.
Right now,
I... just want to see
justice for that poor,
sweet girl.
Ms. Kean,
I need you to understand two things.
One,
Oswald did not kill Isabella;
and two, he's not in love with me.
Are you so certain?
Don't you owe it to her to find out?
Let me know how it goes.
The Court of Owls maintains a
number of buildings in Gotham.
This one is rarely occupied
and always well guarded,
and there are two alarms.
The first covers points of entry.
Last week, we managed to
disarm one of the windows.
Once inside, the front door
can be opened using a code
that we possess.
The second alarm is in the basement.
In the room with the safe.
The floor is fitted
with infrared sensors.
You must cross it on a rope.
I have trained for this.
You will give me the key you found,
and I will retrieve the object.
But you still don't know
what the object is, right?
Only that the Court
protects it, fears it.
And that with Talon hunting
us, we have no time.
Right, so...
let's go through this again.
What'd you decide?
We're gonna break in today.
We can't wait any longer.
- You okay?
- Fine.
Just hungry.
GCPD.
Guy named Ryan Pfeffer work here?
Uh, yeah.
It's, uh, sublevel three.
- What, he in trouble?
- He was killed last night.
I need to talk to his colleagues.
You guys keep track of
when key cards are used?
Uh, yeah.
All right.
If anybody uses his, call me.
Sure, but... his was
used 20 minutes ago.
He hasn't logged out.
Call the police. Now.
Jim, Jim.
You're ahead of schedule.
Our paths weren't meant
to cross just yet.
But I'm not gonna kill you yet.
I do that,
you become the martyr,
and she'll carry you
in her heart forever.
No. Before I kill you,
she has to hate you.
And she will.
Come find me, Jim.
So you didn't get a look
at the guy, and he's not
on the cameras. We might get
something off the prints, but...
Doubtful, if he was smart enough
to avoid the cameras. I'm good.
He seems to have been
interested in the research
into Alice Tetch's blood.
Pfeffer's office was ransacked,
and the files were missing.
So someone else is infected with
the virus? That's just great.
It isn't you, is it?
Because that sure
would make things easy.
No, it's not me. What's
that on your hand?
"Arkham."
I didn't write it.
Okay, let's all just calm down.
So the virus-infected
killer wrote on your hand.
He wants you to go to Arkham.
Barnes is in Arkham.
No.
It's not about Barnes.
- Jim, you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Hello, Jervis.
James.
What an unexpected pleasure.
Someone else is infected
with your sister's blood.
You don't say.
And I've been thinking it's possible
she infected them accidentally.
Yes, possible. Possible.
But your reaction tells
me you knew. So...
you infected them after you stole
your sister's blood,
but you stayed quiet,
waiting for them to show symptoms.
Well, that would be darn
sneaky of me, wouldn't it?
I need the name.
Oh.
You need the name.
So... I've been quiet
about it all this time,
and now I'm going to help you
because we're such good friends?
Because I can make your life
here very uncomfortable.
More uncomfortable than having
Captain Barnes next door
screaming "Guilty!"
all hours of the night?
Give me the name!
Oh, James,
I would love to see what
Alice's virus would do to you.
The beast in you is right there.
So desperate to get out.
And I know of whom you speak.
Oh, yes, indeed.
I stabbed him and pricked
him and caused him to bleed.
But nothing you can say,
no words you might possess,
can pry from me the smallest guess,
for this game is my game!
I say when it's done.
And right now I'm having too much fun.
You want to play a game, Jervis?
Fine. Let's play a game.
Whoever you infected...
has some sort of plan.
I want you to tell me
the name of this man.
Wow, James, I...
have to give that effort an "F."
And can you really imagine that...
Two are dead.
More may die soon.
This isn't a game. Give me his name.
You will only know his
name when it's too late!
When the one you love has
been murdered by hate!
Guard! Take me to my cell!
- What do you mean the one that I love?
- Guard!
Give me his name, Tetch.
Give me his name or
you'll share the blame!
Nothing! Nothing! I'll tell you naught!
His name shall be neither
spoken nor taught.
He'll cut and he'll crush
and the blood will run thick.
Though from healer to
killer is no easy trick.
"Healer to killer."
He's a doctor.
My God.
You'll never stop him, James.
He'll kill and he'll kill
- and he'll kill!
- This is Gordon.
Give me Dr. Mario Calvi immediately.
On my damn authority!
Just do it!
I take it you're off?
When we were casing that place,
I got a feeling we were being watched.
And if this Court of
Owls is all you say,
they're not gonna be too cool
with Bruce breaking their deal.
That's very true.
And Master Bruce knows the Court
will catch up with him sooner or later.
And if he has the
opportunity to take them out,
then he'll take them out.
That's a big if.
Especially when your stupid job
is supposed to be protecting him.
My stupid job, miss, is to
make sure that he grows up
to be the man he's meant to be.
Still...
kind of a punk move for him
to make a deal with the
people who killed his parents.
Yeah, well, you understand this, then.
He only did what he did
to protect the people he cares about.
For you.
And it cost him dearly.
Are you serious? Arresting
Don Falcone's son
- on his wedding day?
- I had no choice.
He's got the virus.
Do you really think Lee Thompkins...
Dr. Lee Thompkins...
Wouldn't know if her own
fiancé had the virus?
How long did Barnes have it and hide it?
Tetch must have infected him
that night in the hospital
when he dosed me; it
would explain things.
Like what?
Mario hitting me at
the engagement party.
You know what also would explain that?
You telling Tetch to shoot his fiancée.
You should've seen his face
when those assassins
attacked us... his rage.
He was being attacked by assassins!
What was I supposed to do, Harvey,
wait until he kills
again, till he hurts Lee?
You were supposed to wait
until you had enough proof.
And why would Tetch infect
Mario in the first place?
To hurt me.
Okay, let's say you're right.
Let's say that Mario is infected.
So he crushes some guy's
skull, he breaks into the lab,
he attacks you, and then he
writes "Arkham" on your hand?
Why would he want you to find him?
I don't know.
He doesn't have the virus.
What? No, no, no, no. Run it again.
I ran it three times.
He's clean.
I could've told you that.
But, hey, I'm glad it's official.
Dr. Calvi, on behalf of the GCPD,
I just want to apologize for any...
inconvenience or embarrassment
this may have caused you.
No need.
Living with Lee, I
understand the pressures
you're all under. But
if you'll excuse me,
I have a wedding to attend.
Jim, I understand
this is a tough day for you,
but... no hard feelings.
The test. That's why
you broke into the lab.
To find out how to beat it.
- But why?
- Jim...
I know you have the virus.
I'm gonna prove it.
And I promise, you will never marry Lee.
But she didn't say anything?
She said she thought
we were being watched.
Personally, I think sh-she's
just got the jitters.
She can't still be mad I told
Ivy she was my girlfriend.
Oh.
It just slipped out.
She can call herself whatever she wants.
Fascinating as I find this tale of young
unrequited love is, Master Bruce,
please can we just concentrate
on the task at hand?
Do you have the key?
Excellent.
Alfred, you know when we get this thing,
whatever it is...
the Whispers are gonna
try to take it from us.
Well, to be honest, Master Bruce,
it's not the Whispers I'm worried about.
And have we made any headway
on the waterfront negotiations?
I have spoken with the union leader.
He agreed to our offer.
So those photos can
go back in the vault.
They were quite saucy, weren't they?
And how about the...
Your approval for the new casino
should come through tomorrow.
Demolition can begin right away.
Ed, I cannot tell you
how good it is to see you
back to your old self.
Just one last signature.
This is your resignation.
Isabella's death has altered things,
and I can't continue... No!
Ed, I will not let you leave.
It is not in your best interest.
You have to stay busy.
How can I say this? Um...
We're friends.
Aren't we, Oswald?
Of course!
Since the accident...
And-and I never thought
that this could happen...
I've had the desire to
become more than employer-employee.
More than friends.
I have been feeling the same.
I didn't want to mention it,
because of all the
awfulness about Isabelle.
Isabella!
But...
one cannot deny love.
Wh-What is it? Wh-What's wrong?
There...
there's been a misunderstanding.
I was going to...
propose that we become partners.
Business partners.
Partners?
Then...
Excuse me.
Lee? You here? It's Jim!
Hello, Jim.
I saw you left Lee a message.
I, uh, accidentally took
her phone this morning.
She's not here, by the way.
- Drink?
- No, thanks.
How'd you pass the test?
Because I don't have the virus.
Or do I?
You gonna arrest me, Jim?
Do you want to look even more
like the paranoid ex-lover?
I'll only pass the test again.
We'll find out how you beat it.
Only a matter of time.
Let's say I do have tirus
How would I have gotten it?
From Tet.
Dr. Calvi, I'd like
you to meet my sister,
Alice.
With Barnes...
the virus stoked his
anger at the guilty.
What dark part of me
has it brought to life?
Jealousy.
You're afraid of losing Lee.
If that's true...
that means the woman we
both know you still love
is gonna marry a lunatic
who'll do anything to keep her.
Are you sure you don't want that drink?
What I want to know is why you put me
on your trail.
What are you after?
Let me give you a hint.
You see, what keeps me up at night
is not the thought that you love her.
It's the thought...
that a part of her still loves you.
Well, in that case, let's find her.
Let her decide if she's gonna marry you.
Yeah, I don't think so.
Virus made you strong, not bulletproof.
Let's go.
You know what, Jim, with
all this virus talk,
you keep forgetting one thing.
I'm still Carmine Falcone's son.
You know Victor.
Hi-ho.
Victor, were you listening to him?
He has the same virus as Barnes had.
What's that?
Oh, no. I wasn't listening.
- You have to let me go.
- Uh-huh.
- Does Falcone know you're here?
- Wait.
Wait.
You're free to go, Jim.
I'll keep this.
I don't understand.
I was only supposed to keep you
until the big hand was on
nine and the little hand...
My mag... now.
Sorry, Jim. But, hey, give
the bride a kiss for me.
I asked.
And it is with great pleasure
that I present this
award to Mr. Kyle Davis
for his magnificent book,
an Oral History.
Looks just fascinating.
Thank you.
Oh, you're too kind.
I love sewers.
Ed.
I was worried when you ran off
that I might have upset you.
Can't we just pretend
that nothing happened?
Go back to the way things were?
You are the best friend I've ever had.
I don't want to lose you.
Please?
You're my best friend as well, Oswald.
Remember that.
Jim, what are you doing here?
Are you okay?
Where's Mario?
He's out at the church.
We're about to get married.
You can't marry him.
Oh, my God.
- Just give us a minute.
- Yeah.
Listen to me,
and I know how this is gonna sound...
You think that he has
Alice Tetch's virus.
- He told you.
- Yes.
And he told me that you
had him arrested today,
on our wedding day.
And you had Lucius give him the
test three times, and he passed.
What's wrong with you?
He cheated the test, Lee.
I don't know how, but he did.
Tetch infected him that
night in the hospital.
You went to see Tetch, didn't you?
- Yes.
- Jim,
don't you see?
Tetch is planting ideas in your head.
- No.
- Don't you remember?
He's done this before.
No, this isn't like that.
Okay, what is more likely,
that Tetch is planting ideas
in your head to screw
with you or that Mario
has Alice's virus?
Lee, you cannot marry him!
Mario said that you would
never let us be happy.
I thought he was
overreacting, but he's right.
Tetch or not, you are obsessed.
Let it go.
This is what he wanted.
- What are you talking about?
- This.
Me coming here.
That's why he put me on his trail.
He got the test so he could
find out how to beat it.
He had me arrest him so
I'd look like a jealous ex.
That's why Zsasz let me
go, so I'd race here...
finally push you away.
Oh, Jim.
I say this as someone
who cares about you.
Get help.
I love you.
I've never stopped.
I should've come to see you as
soon as I got out of prison,
but I couldn't.
I was ashamed.
I thought I had to set things right.
But I did finally come,
Lee.
I saw you,
through the window, with him.
You were smiling.
You looked happy.
I couldn't bring myself to go in.
I've regretted it every day since.
Please.
Don't marry him.
After the wedding...
Mario and I are leaving Gotham.
I'll never see you again.
- Lee...
- Damn you...
for telling me this now.
You come in here with
these crazy accusations,
and when I don't believe
you, you pull this?
How dare you?!
Don't you see?
- He wants you to hate me.
- Well, he succeeded.
- Get the hell out of here!
- No!
Fine.
Carmine.
Can you please help Detective
Gordon find the exit?
Certainly.
And if you're ready, my dear.
I am.
Do you, Leslie,
take Mario to be your husband?
I do.
And do you,
Mario, take Leslie to be your wife?
I do.
I now pronounce you
husband and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. and Mrs. Calvi.
Well, I think it's safe to admit
that our foreign friends
are no-show, Master Bruce.
It was a right dodgy plan, anyway.
Where are you going?
That would be home.
Alfred, this is our only
shot to take down the Court.
You don't know that, do you?
I mean, it was a moot point, anyway.
I mean, walking across the
entire length of a room
on a bloody tightrope?
I can do it. I... I did it.
Yeah, three times out of 20. I counted.
No, thank you very much.
I can do it.
Oh, that's bloody marvelous, isn't it?
Hey?
Right.
you stay on comms
at all times.
If I order abort, you
abort. Is that clear?
I need my head examined.
Really do.
What?
Just wondering.
Does this mean you are my girlfriend?
Shut up.
So, I thought, if I were Mario,
how would I beat the test?
Well, the test looks for
this one marker in the blood,
but that marker can be
masked by an abundance
of certain other drugs.
The two most easily available,
Cloracinamine and...
Lucius, just-just get to the point.
Mario's blood came back off
the charts for Cloracinamine.
Alvarez!
Get a unit on Lee Thompkins
and Dr. Mario Calvi,
and don't let them out of your sight!
This isn't proof that Mario
killed those men.
No, but it's enough
for a search warrant.
Now I got to go find Jim Gordon.
Don't mess with Falcone!
Hey.
All right, straight to the safe room.
I'm gonna check the rest of the house.
Go on. This way.
Not exactly hiding it.
There's no point.
The floor is alarmed.
Don't... let... go.
Come on!
Out the way you came!
- Let's go!
- No!
No!
We have to leave.
And who exactly are you?
You're the one who's been
following us.
Hey.
You know her?
That's my mom.
Now can we get out of here?
You're bloody right.
Found it! In his trash.
Cloracinamine.
Oh, yes.
We got him.
Tell Alvarez.
That was Alvarez.
Lee and Mario snuck
out of the reception.
He lost them.
I can't even hold a knife.
I swear, when I see Nygma...
We'll kill him together. Real slow.
How sweet.
Son of a bitch!
Hear him out.
Please.
I don't want to kill him.
I want to destroy him.
I want to take...
away...
everything that he loves.
I want to make him...
despised.
What are you talking about?
Penguin.
- He killed the librarian.
- What?
And you cut off my hand?!
I assume you want something.
With Penguin gone,
the underworld will need a new leader.
I think it's time Gotham
had a woman's touch.
The crime families
will never follow you.
Well, that's where you come in.
You know the families in and out.
Not to mention, you're a whiz
at strategy.
Think about it, Ed.
Your brains, their brawn,
my...
me.
We could make quite a team.
We destroy Penguin first.
Of course.
But there is one thing you need to do.
Okay.
I'm sorry about your hand.
Apology not accepted!
Well, we'll work on that.
Drinks!
Hey.
Thank you.
Thank you for letting us
leave that party early.
Hmm, of course.
I wanted to.
I love this house.
It's my father's refuge.
Not many people know about it.
I know Gordon came to the church.
Talked to you.
It was just like you said.
He said you had the virus.
He was obsessed.
And what did you say?
That after the wedding, we
would be leaving Gotham.
That I would never see him again.
Is that it?
What are you asking me?
I'm asking...
if there's any part
of you, however small,
that still has feelings for him.
And I swear,
I will never ask you again.
A part of me will always care for him.
But I married you.
I love you.
That's all I needed to know.
Where are they?
Don Falcone, he just...
Where are they?!
You don't give up, do you?
Your son has Alice Tetch's virus.
He's killed two people we know of.
Every cop in this city is after him.
Where is he?
You knew?
That Mario had the same virus as Barnes?
No.
I knew he was in danger,
but I didn't know why.
I never suspected this.
You're saying the attacks
on Mario... the car bomb...
It's because of the virus?
How is that possible?
Who knew he had it?
I can't tell you that.
I'll send my men to bring Mario in.
You think I'd trust Lee's
life with these two goons?
Tell me where they are.
If I do that, you'll kill him.
I know you, James.
Mario is my son.
There is nothing and no
one more valuable to me.
And if he does have this
sickness, he needs help.
And if he kills Lee, he'll cross a line
he'll never come back from.
Even if he's cured, knowing
that will destroy him.
I'm your only hope.
Still, I'll send my men.
You mean these two?
Anyone else you want to send?
Swear that you'll brg him in alive.
I swear.
Now, where are they?
She loves him.
Loves him!
She loves him. Loves him.
She loves him. She loves him.
She loves him.
She loves him. Loves him.
She loves him. She loves him.
Lee!
Jim?
www.tvsubtitles.net